# MICHAEL BRIAN WARD

FRONT-END DEVELOPER REACT/JS

### **PROFILE**

I have a very mixed background when it comes to my job experience, but every job I had I received promotions and ended up taking on a leadership role. I have always taken pride in my work, and for the first time in my life I feel I am where I belong with coding.

# CONTACT EMAIL

thewardbunch@gmail.com

### **PORTFOLIO**

https://bwardstories.github.io/portfolio/

#### LINKEDIN

https://tinyurl.com/w3tp4naw

# PHONE/CITY/STATE

(843) 214-3314

Bonneau, SC 29431

## **EXPERIENCE**

### LEAD ELECTRICIAN, ELITE ELECTRIC CO., SUMMERVILLE, SC

JAN 2017-MAR 2020

Purchased materials for jobs, supervised training of new hires, assigned tasks for workers, kept track of total man hours up to 8 workers per job, made sure all work passed inspections. 100% passed inspections rate for term of employment

# PAWN SHOP MANAGER, MONEY MAN PAWN, SUMMERVILLE, SC

APRIL 2012- NOV 2016

Oversaw training for new hires, managed annual payroll budget of over \$500,000 for 11 employees, researching items and qualifying loans on said items.

### STORE MANAGER, DOLLAR GENERAL, CROSS, SC

MAY 2009- APRIL 2012

Managed annual payroll budget of \$300,000 for up to 10 employees, purchasing merchandise to keep store stocked, training new hires

### STORE MANAGER, MONEY MAN PAWN, SUMMERVILLE, SC

NOV 2006- MAY 2009

Responsible for training new hires, managing payroll budget, researching items and qualifying loans on said items.

### LEAD ELECTRICIAN, ELITE ELECTRIC CO., SUMMERVILLE, SC

APRIL 1999 - NOV 2006

Purchased materials for jobs, supervised training of new hires, assigned tasks for workers, kept track of total man hours for job.

### **EDUCATION**

#### FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPEMENT

KENZIE ACADEMY, INDIANAPOLIS IN APRIL 2021

# LANGUAGES, OTHER SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, C#, Express, Zustand, Bootstrap, MongoDB, APIs, Git, Data Structures, Deployment, RESTful APIs,